<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
----Stories from the Zone----

---Btucher---

--Quest1 now 3--
	
<string id="butcher_1_start_0">
		<text>You said there was a lost cargo?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_1_start_1">
		<text>Yeah - a scientist, Vybegallo, over in Agroprom contacted me because his order got lost in the marshes. A substantial food delivery apparently - the small probably attracted a dogs 
		and the delivery guy decided his life was more important than the job and threw the cargo to them in order to distract the pack. Everything happened quite fast, so he doesn't remember the exact size of that pack, but he said there were a shit ton of them, so I guess there should be a dozen.
		\n \n Do you think you can recover the package and deliver it to that scientist?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_1_start_2">
		<text>Sure, I’m up for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_1_start_3">
		<text>Thanks, but I’m not ready yet.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_1_start_4">
		<text>Alright. According to his report he got jumped by them near an old construction site. The guy made his way past the Pump Station and kept the village with the water tower to his left, and the village the military sometimes uses to his right. Your job is to recover the package, there is no bounty on the dogs.
	If you found the package, deliver it to Vybegallo, he is somewhere in the Agroprom fabric.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_1_start_5">
		<text>No problem, come back later.</text>
	</string>	

<string id="butcher_1_time_0">
		<text>About your lost package.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_1_time_1">
		<text>Yes, are you ready?</text>
	</string>

<string id="butcher_1_done_0">
		<text>I delivered the package.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_1_done_1">
		<text>Well done! Keep the reward money, you deserve it. If you're ready, the snork problem requires some more attention.</text>
	</string>
	
-- Quest 2 --

<string id="butcher_2_start_0">
		<text>Do you have some special jobs for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_2_start_1">
		<text>I heard of some of your exploits, you seem like the capable kind… \n \nYou see, Duty pays me to keep the road from Cordon to Rostok free from particularly dangerous mutant threats – the sort the rookies wouldn’t be able to handle. You know, good for business and so on. Luckily the really dangerous mutants are rather rare in these parts. 
		\n \n Most of the times my problems here are rather that packs of animals grow to a threatening number -  and exactly such a problem emerged. A sow gave birth to a litter of piglets a couple of months ago, reports vary on their number. Some say three, others believe to have seen six. 
		Be as it may, I need you to put and end to them before the piglets grow to adult boars – I don’t need to tell you what a problem that would be. So what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_2_start_2">
		<text>Consider it done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_2_start_3">
		<text>I need some time to prepare.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_2_start_4">
		<text>That’s the spirit! They inhabit the small wood in the south east, behind the Witches Jelly anomaly. Here take these, they should come in handy! Come see me when they’re dead, I’ll have put some vodka put to the side for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_2_start_5">
		<text>No problem, come see me when you’re ready!</text>
	</string>		
	
	<string id="butcher_2_time_0">
		<text>Concerning that job.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_2_time_1">
		<text>Are you ready to take on the boars?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="butcher_2_done_0">
		<text>The boars are no more.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_2_done_1">
		<text>Well done! Here, have some booze and some food – on the house! And of course, a reward for your troubles. Have a rest and if you want more work – there is something urgent.</text>
	</string>
	
	
-- Quest 3 --

<string id="butcher_3_start_0">
		<text>You said there was an urgent task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_3_start_1">
		<text>Indeed. \n \n A group of snorks got lost and wandered over here from Agroprom. This happens sometimes, but in the past it always was one or two who found a way here - this time the reports talk about four! We can't let them dwell there, they pose too large a threat to the rookies. So what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_3_start_2">
		<text>They are as good as dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_3_start_3">
		<text>I need some time to prepare.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_3_start_4">
		<text>Alright! They took up residence south west from here,near the southern path to Agroprom... Here take this, they should come in handy! Come see me when they’re dead, we'll raise a glass to your deeds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_3_start_5">
		<text>No problem, come see me when you’re ready!</text>
	</string>		
	
	<string id="butcher_3_time_0">
		<text>Concerning that job.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_3_time_1">
		<text>Are you ready to take on the snorks?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="butcher_3_done_0">
		<text>The snorks are dead.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_3_done_1">
		<text>Well done! Here, have a drink and some food. Here, have a smoke too. And of course, a reward for your troubles. Have a rest and come see me - I have a job for you concerning some lost cargo in the Swamp.</text>
	</string>	
	
-- Quest 4 --

<string id="butcher_4_start_0">
		<text>You said you wanted to talk to me about the snork problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_start_1">
		<text>Yes. \n \nYou see, this snork incursion worries me. It sometimes happened in the past, but never in these numbers! I've been thinking, probably the snork population in Agroprom grew too much and that's the reason why they come over in larger numbers now... Can you have a look and if my suspicion is right - cull them? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_start_2">
		<text>I will take a look.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_start_3">
		<text>I need some time to prepare.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_4_start_4">
		<text>Alright! Don't go alone, Ilya over there will accompany you - fear not he's a capable fighter. Travel over to Agroprom, if my suspicions are true, they should be somewhere between the southern and the northern path to Garbage. 
		There is a hill there, chances are good that's where you'll find them. Take this, you will need it. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_start_5">
		<text>No problem, come see me when you’re ready!</text>
	</string>		
	
	<string id="butcher_4_time_0">
		<text>Concerning that job.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_4_time_1">
		<text>Are you ready to cull the snork population?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="butcher_4_done_0">
		<text>The snorks are dead.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_4_done_1">
		<text>Well done! Here, have a drink and a bite. So tell me, how is the snork situation over there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_done_2">
		<text>You were right, we killed at least ten snorks! It was a massacre, I'm glad we made it out alive!</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="butcher_4_done_3">
		<text>Ten of these pieces of shit? Fuck... good that I send both you and Ilya to take care of the problem... We will have to keep an eye on this situation - this is very strange. 
		\n \nThanks for your help! Take a rest, and if you feel able to do some work again, go meet Aspirin, the Duty medic. He contacted me, seems they need some discrete help. </text>
	</string>			

---- Quest 5 ----
<string id="st_butcher_5_help_info">
		<text>Butcher: My friend, we need your urgent help. Ilya has been wounded in Agroprom and the other hunter, Orion, is missing in action. Please, go as soon as possible to Agroprom and find Ilya in the factory - he will be able to give you details.</text>
	</string>



<string id="butcher_5_start_0">
		<text>I got your message, what is going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_start_1">
		<text>Good that you're here - Ilya set off with another hunter, Orion, to find the cause of that Snork infestation. They were able to trace it back to the Agroprom Underground - 
		apparently something in there drives the Snorks out. Both of them undertook the mission to explore the Underground, but Ilya got wounded. They returned, but Orion set off again... young fool... that was yesterday and since then we haven't heard of him.
		I now this is a lot to ask, but can you go down there and check the situation out? We expect the worst, but we can't leave a brother behind. \n \nWould you be ready for such an undertaking?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_start_2">
		<text>Yes, of course, I'll head over there now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_start_3">
		<text>I don't know, that sounds very dangerous. I will have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_start_4">
		<text>Great! Find Ilya, he is recovering from his wounds in the Agroprom Factory. And here, take this - you will need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_start_5">
		<text>Understandable - but I'm afraid to insist on the urgency of this matter. Go find Ilya if you believe you're up to it.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ilya_muromets_3_0">
		<text>I got the message from Butcher, what is going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_3_1">
		<text>Good that you're here - we ran into some trouble and I'm wounded... I will make it, don't worry, but I'm incapacitated. I came here with another hunter - Orion, a young blood, to find the cause of that Snork infestation. We noticed that during the night, a lot of these bastards came pouring out of the Underground.
		There is something down there that drives them out - something nefarious... We went down there and it was brutal... our heads began to hurt and suddenly we were surrounded by Snorks and I got bitten in the arm and leg - luckily Orion was there to carry me out! But... that fool went back! I begged him to wait, but he was eager, how young people are!
		Shit, and now I haven't heard of him. My friend, please go down there and find him! I would like to come with you, but my leg won't carry me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_3_2">
		<text>Don't worry, I'll find Orion and bring him back here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_3_3">
		<text>I don't know, I don't think I'm ready to head down there yet!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_3_4">
		<text>I know I could count on you! And here, take this - I'm afraid you might need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_3_5">
		<text>Understandable - but please hurry! And here, take this - if you're ready to go down there, I'm afraid you might need it.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ilya_muromets_4_0">
		<text>I found Orion...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_4_1">
		<text>I understand... What got him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_4_2">
		<text>I... I'm not sure. There is a huge room underneath, with somemachinery... and there was a Controller surrounded by Snorks and Burers who tried to protect him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_4_3">
		<text>A Controller? You don't say... and he was friendly with the Snorks? I thought these mutants hated each other? Strange... I don't understand - if the Snorks were friendly to him, why did they flee the Underground?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_4_4">
		<text>I don't know man... but he had an army surrounding him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_4_5">
		<text>This place will never stop to confuse me. You know what, it's time for you to speak to Forester. After what you did here for us, you deserve to become part of our guild. I'm sure Butcher will vouch for you too! Go see him, and tell him what you saw down under.
		 I'll stay here for a while to recover and keep an eye on the situation. I'll find you later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_4_6">
		<text>Guild?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ilya_muromets_4_7">
		<text>Yeah man, a guild - or how Forester likes to call it, a Brotherhood. Go see him, he'll be able to explain all of this much better than I can.</text>
	</string>


--- Ilya Muromets ---
<string id="ilya_muromets_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello Stalker, how can I help you?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ilya_muromets_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Hello, who are you?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ilya_muromets_start_dialog_2">
		<text>I'm Ilya Muromets, but you can call me Ilya. I'm an old friend of Butcher. </text>
	</string>	

<string id="ilya_muromets_1_0">
		<text>Are you ready to go hunt some snorks?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ilya_muromets_1_1">
		<text>Yeah, butcher told me to give you a hand. Lead the way, I'm behind you.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ilya_muromets_2_0">
		<text>That was brutal!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ilya_muromets_2_1">
		<text>Yeah, I never saw that many Snorks in one spot! This is very very strange - I will have to investigate. Thanks a lot for your help - you're quite good at thisu!</text>
	</string>

	
--- Hunter Duty ---	
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_0">
		<text>Butcher told me you might have a job for me.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_1">
		<text>Ah right! Thanks for coming.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_2">
		<text>No problem, how can I help?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_3">
		<text>Right. To make it short, the boys here have some trouble on their hands. Voronin recently went to a meeting with Sakharov and Kuznetsov to discuss some general matters. During that meeting, Sakharov asked Voronin to help them by clearing the Bloodsucker Village, a proposition Kuznetsov apparently laughed at, saying Duty wasn't able to manage that and he proposed the help of his soldiers instead.
			Voronin took that very badly, and started to boast about our boys capabilities. Nothing bad at defending the honour of our soldiers, but he lost any touch to reality and promised Sakharov to clear out the Bloodsucker Village for them. Problem is, he wants to do it overnight in order for the Ecologists to show up in the morning and find a safe village... Over fucking night! Can you imagine? 
		He wants to show off in front of the military, you understand - and this asshole doesn't care about the fact that some of them won't survive the night. \n \nOf course the boys are less than enthusiastic to lose their lifes for the General's ego, they are soldiers after all, no Spetsnaz.
		So they came to me, and I promised to see what I can do - I thought of Butcher and asked if he couldn't send us an experiencied hunter who is up to the job. Of course you need to be discrete, Vornonin can't know anything about this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_4">
		<text>I'm all ears.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_5">
		<text>Clearing out the Bloodsucker Village during night? That's suicide!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_6">
		<text>"We are not to reason why, we are but to do and die." Orders are orders, I don't condone insubordination!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_7">
		<text>I'm glad to hear that, it is always nice to talk to professionals. Of course we don't expect you doing it for free, the boys will pitch in to reward you for your help! 
		They even managed to bribe Mangun to give them a nightvision device - so you won't have to go in blind like a mole. So you're in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_8">
		<text>Yes it's tough, but think about it - if someone can do it, it's certainly you! Butcher told me about your skills hunting mutants - that's more than I can say about our boys. Of course we don't expect you doing it for free, the boys will pitch in to reward you for your help! 
		They even managed to bribe Mangun to give them a nightvision device - so you won't have to go in blind like a mole. Will you help us? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_9">
		<text>I understand the need for a soldier to follow orders of his superiors, but this is objectively not a sane mission! These are actual people being send for a mission they haven't trained for! Think of it! You on the other hand have experience in these matters, 
		at least Butcher told me that you are skilled in hunting mutants. And of course we don't expect you doing it for free, the boys will pitch in to reward you for your help! 
		They even managed to bribe Mangun to give them a nightvision device - so you won't have to go in blind like a mole. So you're in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_10">
		<text>Alright, I will do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_11">
		<text>I can do it, but I want Voronin to know it was me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_12">
		<text>I need some time to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_13">
		<text>No way, they can do it themselves!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_14">
		<text>God bless you. Come see me the night you want to do it, I'll give you the nightvision device and warn the boys they should pretend to leave for the raid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_15">
		<text>That's not possible, Voronin wants it to be the guys designated by him. Can you not do it for them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_16">
		<text>Alright, but please don't take too long, Voronin grows impatient.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_17">
		<text>Are you sure? Think about it, the guys would really appreciate it!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_time_0">
		<text>About the Bloodsucker Village.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_time_1">
		<text>Yeah? Are you up to it?</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_no_1">
		<text>Yeah? Did you change your mind?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_no_13">
		<text>I decided, I will certainly not do it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_no_17">
		<text>*Sigh* A shame, I had high hopes for you, but alright... I'll ask Butcher if he can send me someone else...</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_0">
		<text>About the Bloodsucker Village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_1">
		<text>Yes, what about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_2">
		<text>I am ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_3">
		<text>I am ready.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_4">
		<text>I am not ready yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_5">
		<text>Good to hear that, come see me this night before you set off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_6">
		<text>Perfect. Here is your nightvision device - I also packed some batteries so that you won't find yourself in the middle of night without juice. Take these medics too, hopefully you won't need them, but better safe than sorry.
		You have to be back in six hours, before the Ecologists will set off! Good hunting Stalker, and thanks for helping us out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_7">
		<text>Alright, come see me when you are.</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_1_0">
		<text>The job is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_1_1">
		<text>Excellent work! I knew you would pull through!</text>
	</string>	

<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_2_0">
		<text>I'm sorry, I couldn't get the job done in time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_2_1">
		<text>Don't worry Stalker! We will get some scolding from Voronin, but at least no life is lost.</text>
	</string>	
	

<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_0">
		<text>What happened in the Bloodsucker Village?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_1">
		<text>You ratted us out, that's what happened. Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_2">
		<text>I believe in following orders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_3">
		<text>I wanted to see what would happen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_4">
		<text>I did it for the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_5">
		<text>You're an asshole. You could simply have ignored this and we would have hired someone else - instead three of our boys are dead and Artyom is in a critical condition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_6">
		<text>You wanted to see what would happen? Three dead - one wounded - that's what would happen! You're an asshole - get lost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_7">
		<text>For the money? You're an asshole - your greed cost the life of our boys!</text>
	</string>

<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_0">
		<text>What happened to the guy on the floor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_1">
		<text>Artyom - a collateral of your ratting. Artyom is the only survivor - he managed to run away when everything went to shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_2">
		<text>Will he make it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_3">
		<text>Probably yeah, I managed to stabilize him. But he still is in great pain and he seems to be badly traumatized - he has panic fits and I have to give him Morphine in order to calm him down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_4">
		<text>I'm sorry for what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_5">
		<text>Humpf. Your regret will not bring back Vadim, Sasha and Sergey, but at least you admit to your fault.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_6">
		<text>Don't try to pin this on me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_7">
		<text>Fuck off asshole, this is your fault. </text>
	</string>

<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_0">
		<text>I need to tell you something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_1">
		<text>What are you waiting for, speak up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_2">
		<text>Your men tried to pay me to clear the Bloodsucker village for them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_3">
		<text>Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_4">
		<text>What? Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_5">
		<text>Then stop wasting my time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_6">
		<text>They are afraid to do it - they say that they are not trained for such a night mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_7">
		<text>These cowards... I will beat bravery into them - thanks for telling me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_8">
		<text>It was me who cleared the Bloodsucker Village - your men payed me to do the job in their stead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_9">
		<text>What? Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_10">
		<text>They were too afraid to do it - they said that they are not trained for such a night mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_11">
		<text>These cowards... I will beat bravery into them - thanks for telling me! 
		Here have a "fee" to keep your mouth shut, we can't have this disgrace be known in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_0">
		<text>You wanted to see me?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1">
		<text>Yes... I'm afraid that the mission failed. Of the four men I send only one made it back - badly wounded and out of his mind. 
				We barely got anything out of him, but it seems that it went to shit the moment they set foot into that Village.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_2">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_3">
		<text>Artyom wasn't able to give a full report...  from what I understood, they didn’t follow protocol and separated which resulted in a mission failure. 
		He's with Aspirin at the moment, maybe you can get something out of him. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_4">
		<text>What do you want me to do about the situation?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_5">
		<text>No one can know about this failure and my men refuse to go back to that Village during night. 
			I need someone to sneak into the village during night and swap the fallen men's Duty patch with Mercenary ones... </text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_6">
		<text>What? Are you fucking kidding me?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_7">
		<text>Understandable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_8">
		<text>Not at all, this is vital for the reputation of Duty - we can not be allowed to show weakness!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_9">
		<text>I'm glad that we are on the same page - the reputation of Duty is after all paramount.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_10">
		<text>Can you not simply recover their bodies?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_11">
		<text>Out of question! That would draw too much attention to the failure - I cannot allow it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_111">
		<text>But these man died in the line of duty! You have to recover them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_112">
		<text>These men knew for what they signed up. Besides, the reputation of Duty is larger than the memory of a few men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_12">
		<text>Why Mercenary patches?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_13">
		<text>Isn't it obvious? To make it look as if some Mercenaries dressed as Duty soldiers in order to bypass Rostok without unnecessary attention, but got caught in the Bloodsucker Village. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_14">
		<text>Alright, I will help you clean up the evidence.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_15">
		<text>I have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_16">
		<text>I don't want to be involved in this.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_17">
		<text>Good. Prepare for the mission and come see me during the night before you set off.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_18">
		<text>Then do it fast, the more time passes the more people will notice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_19">
		<text>Are you sure? I'm ready to pay a good price for this, let's say 20.000 roubles?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_20">
		<text>For that price I can do it.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_21">
		<text>No forget it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_22">
		<text>Good. Prepare for the mission and come see me during the night before you set off.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_23">
		<text>Think about it.</text>
	</string>

<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_0">
		<text>About the mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_1">
		<text>Yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_2">
		<text>I am ready. Tell me about the details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_3">
		<text>Perfect. The mission is rather simple, you find the bodies of Vadim, Sergey and Sasha and replace their Duty patch with these ones. But be careful to finsih the job before sunrise, we can't have anyone seeing you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_4">
		<text>I need some more time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_5">
		<text>Alright, but please hurry up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_6">
		<text>I have changed my mind - I will assist you with your cover up..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_7">
		<text>Alright, good to hear! Come see me when you are ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_8">
		<text>Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_9">
		<text>Okay...?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_10">
		<text>I am ready, tell me about the details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_11">
		<text>Good, come see me during the night beofre setting of.</text>
	</string>

<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_2_0">
		<text>It is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_2_1">
		<text>Excellent work Stalker - now no one will be able to pin anything on Duty. Here is your reward - I hope I can count on your discression.</text>
	</string>

<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_3_0">
		<text>It is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_3_1">
		<text>You mean you failed - there is chatter about a Stalker fumbling with Duty bodies in the Bloodsucker village. Here some compensation, but I believe it's also in your best interest to keept your failure secret.</text>
	</string>	

	
<string id="st_dolg_voronin_bloodsucker_news_0">
		<text>Voronin: Stalker, we have a problem on our hands. Please come see me as soon as possible!</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_dolg_aspirin_bloodsucker_news_0">
		<text>Aspirin: Stalker, come see me - we have a job proposition for you.</text>
	</string>	
<string id="st_dolg_aspirin_bloodsucker_news_1">
		<text>Aspirin: Stalker, come see me - we got a problem for which we need your help.</text>
	</string>	
<string id="st_freedom_voronin_bloodsucker_news_0">
		<text>Yo guys, there is a Stalker looting... Duty soldiers? Dead Duty soldiers in the Bloodsucker Village? What are they doing there?</text>
	</string>	
	
	

<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_0">
		<text>You said you have a job offer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_1">
		<text>Yes - the boys want to get vengeance on these Bloodsuckers and considering that you have... 
	experience with that Village, they would like you to join them on their expedition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_2">
		<text>So you're not taking it badly that I told Voronin and accepted his job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_3">
		<text>Well... obviously that was not very cool of you - we could have hired someone else who would have done it instead of you.
	But... I - We understand that the Zone is not very conductive for morals and that people like you are here for... their personal gains.
	Water under the Bridge, you didn't kill Sasha, Sergey and Vadim, these fucking Bloodsuckers did it... now we would like to hire you for payback. 
	A lot of money Stalker, the boys didn't clutch their wallets in order to get payback.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_4">
		<text>No bad feelings about Artyom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_5">
		<text>Artyom, yes, that was - to be frank - quite stupid of you to give him that much morphine. Poor Artyom... He didn't deserve to die like this. 
	But life goes on ... let's not talk about Artyom, yes? His death is still very painfull to me.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_6">
		<text>What is the plan? Isn't a night raid too dangerous?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_7">
		<text>No night raid needed Stalker, the plan is quite different. We bought all the explosives we could get our hands on, and we will set them up in different locations of the village showing Bloodsucker activity.
		When they creep out during the night, we will blow them up like firework!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_8">
		<text>Alright, I'm in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_9">
		<text>I have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_10">
		<text>No, I think I will not help you out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_11">
		<text>We are glad to hear that! Come see me when you're ready, and I tell you the details!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_12">
		<text>Alright, but please hurry! The boys are getting restless waiting for their vengeance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_13">
		<text>Are you sure? There is a lot of money to be made and the job is quite easy if I dare to say so.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_14">
		<text>Let me think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_15">
		<text>No, my answer is final.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_16">
		<text>Alright, take your time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_17">
		<text>Please consider the job offer! We will be waiting if you change your mind.</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_0">
		<text>About the payback mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_1">
		<text>Yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_2">
		<text>I am ready. Tell me about the details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_3">
		<text>Good, very good. Ilya Kovalyov is your contact person - you will meet him in Army Warehouse in the farm south of the path leading here.
	Wait for him there - he will explain the rest of the mission to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_4">
		<text>I need some more time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_5">
		<text>Alright, but please hurry up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_6">
		<text>I have changed my mind - I will assist you taking vengeance on these Bloodsuckers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_7">
		<text>Alright, the boys will be happy to hear that! Come see me when you are ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_8">
		<text>Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_9">
		<text>Okay...?</text>
	</string>

<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_5_0">
		<text>You asshole set me up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_5_1">
		<text>Fuck you, you deserve it asshole!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_5_2">
		<text>Your friends were about to kill me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_5_3">
		<text>I told them to only fuck you up, but I can't blame them for hating your guts. Now fuck off asshole!</text>
	</string>

	
<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_0">
		<text>Good day asshole.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_1">
		<text>What? What is your problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_2">
		<text>Was it not enough for you to rat us out? 
	Did you have to accept Voronin's request and let our boys lie abandoned in that fucking Village while everyone is supposed to pretend they are mercenaries?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_3">
		<text>Relax, it was not personal, only business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_4">
		<text>Aspirin told us to give you a good beating, but you don't deserve that. This is for the boys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_5">
		<text>Woah what are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_7">
		<text>What? And Artyom? Did you have to kill that poor soul? You're scum!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_8">
		<text>I - it was not my intention!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Ah ah ah... it hurts... please help me...</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_0">
		<text>Artyom, I need to ask you something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_1">
		<text>Ah ah ah...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_2">
		<text>Where can I find the bodies of the other soldiers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_3">
		<text>Ah ah ah... my leg, it hurts. Mother please! I want to go home</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_4">
		<text>[Morphine] Here take the morphine, it will help with the pain. Can you remember what happened during that night?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_5">
		<text>Aaaaah... fuck... \n \n... \n \nWhere am I, what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_6">
		<text>Relax, you're back in the base. I need you to remember what happened during the raid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_7">
		<text>What? The raid? ... Yes the raid ... \n \n ... \n \nfuck the raid ... it was a massacer, we should never have gone into that Village. We entered from the south-west, and everything was quiet - we even made it across the dirt raod withouth incident...
			But when we approached the wooden house everything... everything... oh my god Vadim! Vadim! Aaaaah!!! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_8">
		<text>Relax Artyom, relax! Tell me what happened next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_9">
		<text>I believe that is enough... rest well Artyom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_10">
		<text>Vadim! Aaah it hurts... Vadim!!! Sergey!!! Mother!!! HELP! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_11">
		<text>[Morphine] Here take the morphine... Artyom, what happened after Vadim died?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_12">
		<text>Aaaaah... \n \n ... \n \nWhat? Ah yes... after the Bloodsucker slaughtered Vadim we turned around and ran for our lifes... Sergey was first ... faster than Sasha and me ... he ran into the first house he saw... \n \n ... \n \n
			We heard ... we heard a horrible screach ... followed by a scream! They got Sasha ... they got Sasha... oh my god, why? Why? Ohhhhhhh...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_13">
		<text>Artyom relax! We are nearly done Artyom! What happened next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_14">
		<text>Aaaaah!!! They're everywhere! Help! Please help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_15">
		<text>[Morphine] Here some more morphine... Artyom, we nearly finished, what happened after Sergey died?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_16">
		<text>Oh... aaaaah... \n \n ... \n \n yes the raid... we ... we didn't follow Sergey into that ... house. Sasha went totally mad ... went off towards the heart of the village... I... didn't think ... followed him ... we ... ran ... until we ... north of village...
			There we found... a house ... empty... we rested... yes rested ... I'm tired ... I need to rest ... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_17">
		<text>Artyom! Artyom!!! Don't fall asleep!!! Artyom, wake up!!!</text>
	</string>
	
------ Forester -------
<string id="forester_mutanthammer_0">
		<text>[Mutanthammer] I found this gun on [XXX].</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_mutanthammer_1">
		<text>Ah yes, the Mutanthammer. I remember this gun, it was me who modified it! 
			Mainly I fluted the barrel and replaced some of it's components with a lighter material to cut off some weight. Of course it also comes with a downside - the gun will wear faster than a standard Saiga.
			Took me some time, but I'm really proud of it. So you're the new owner - I hope it will serve you well! Here, let me clean it for you and repair it in order to make it pristine again. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_mutanthammer_2">
		<text>Thank you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_mutanthammer_3">
		<text>No problem! \n \n...\n \n Here, as good as new! Good hunting with it!</text>
	</string>

<string id="forester_legendary_0_0">
		<text>What's the story behind that Bloodsucker trophy?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_1">
		<text>Oh that's Moloch - the brother of Vlad and Drakul.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_2">
		<text>Moloch? Vlad? Drakul? Since when do mutants have names?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_3">
		<text>Since I gave a name to these mutants. Of course they are not any Bloodsuckers - they are very ancient beings... they've been around since the earlier days of the Zone - and around here, being old means something.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_04">
		<text>Vlad and Drakul? That doesn't sound very original for Bloodsuckers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_05">
		<text>I don't care if it's original, what matters to me is that it suits them. Besides, if you believe you're more creative - find a mutant deserving a name and prove it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_4">
		<text>Brothers? How do you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_5">
		<text>I don't know - but for me they are brothers. I met them together - here in this forest. The first Bloodsuckers I've ever seen, I didn't know that such devils could even exist... but they do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_6">
		<text>What is the story behind them?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_7">
		<text>Where to begin? From where they came - I don't know... But I still remember the first time I met them. It was not long after the second great explosion, the one which created this hell. 
			I picked up a distress radio call of survivors - a military scout squad which got lost in the Zaton swamps. Apparently their commander walked into a Vortex and with him their only map got shredded. 
			Imagine giving only one map for a whole squad - but it seems some things didn't change since the old days. Nevertheless, I found the two survivors and promised to lead them back to their headquarters - back in the days the Military still had a presence in the Army Warehouses.
			We reached this forest at dusk - I wanted to overnight at this complex, but these boys were eager to rejoin their base. Nowadays, crossing the forest at night would mean certain death, but you know back then most of these mutants were quite rare and didn't yet reach the southern parts of the Zone. 
			So we made a compromise - we were to take a rest and have something to eat and continue our journey after having warmed our bellies with food and our spirit with vodka. We entered the forest to gather some firewood and cooked some meat on a clearing. I don't know what attracted them - the smell of food or maybe the laughter...
			I left the fireplace to take a piss while the two soldiers continued fooling around. When returned to the fire I saw one of them lying on the ground - hissing from laughter I thought... it was only when I stood next to him that I noticed the blood gurgling out of his throat. I looked up - the other stood there with wide eyes and behind him...
			I don't know which of the brothers it was, but that was the first Bloodsucker I saw in my life. I didn't understand - I simply froze. That's when I felt tentacles grapling around my neck - strong and hot was that grip! I wasn't thinking - I grabbed a piece of burning wood and struck behind me! 
			The Bloodsucker immediately let go of me, and I scrambled off, running for my life! That's how I met Moloch, Vlad and Drakul! 
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_8">
		<text>Damn... but you managed to shoot Moloch? How did that happen?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_9">
		<text>I met the brothers many times since then! At first I shunned that forest, until I noticed that they are night creatures. I started to track them, gather informations on this new danger lurking in my wood. I tried to lay traps - the first worked but I wasn't able to capitalise on it, but the brothers also learned and started to avoid them.
			Sometimes I managed to wound one - sometimes they managed to wound me. I tried to find their lair by following their foodsteps - to no avail, I never found the exact location. This continued until one day, some bandits tried to jump me. They tried to extort me - I refused. It escalated and they ended up dead - except one! He was wounded and out cold - bleeding to death. 
			So I decided not to let a good corpse go to waste and I carried him into the forest as bait. I tied him to a tree and waited in ambush for the brothers. And sure enough they came - surrounding that poor fellow. Yes, it was not right for me to do that to a fellow man - to expose him to such horros without giving him a fighting chance... But back then I thought it was a good idea.
			While they were gulping on their easy prey, I took aim and patiently waiting for my shot. And I shot - it went right through Moloch's heart. Vlad and Drakul screached up in fright and took off - and I took my trophy. \n \n
			Since then I never saw them again, they retreated deep into the forest and rarely come out anymore - they let most of their hunting be done by their conspecifics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_10">
		<text>Tell me where to find them - I will hunt them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_11">
		<text>I believe that is enough - I still want to be able to sleep.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_12">
		<text>Then you are a fool! They mean certain death - don't be so rash as to believe you'll be able to master them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_13">
		<text>They are mutants, Forester, you don't honestly believe they stopped killing, do you? They have to be destroyed - especially if they are as dangerous as you say!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_14">
		<text>You're right - patience is in order. We have to wait for an opportune moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_15">
		<text>Of course I don't believe they stopped murdering - but it's not your duty putting an end to them! Maybe I wasn't clear enough - they are not your normal Bloodsuckers, they are much worse. They are like a force of nature - we have to live with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_16">
		<text>I protest - I have proven myself, I'm a capable hunter! I faced and mastered many terrors here - I can do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_17">
		<text>I know - you're valant and your skills are great! But this is an order of magnitude which you haven't faced yet - you're overestimating your own strenght - you're rash and want to hurry and this makes you prone to mistakes. Don't ask of me to be guilty of your death - keep your strenght for other mutants, don't waste away your life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_18">
		<text>Forester, have trust in younger people! At some point they have to be stopped, and our chances are better if you would help instead of trying to shelter me. Tell me, how to prepare and I will!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_19">
		<text>Aah, young people... so overconfident. You don't understand - you will not face them alone, but also their brethren! \n \n... \n \nBut I can see it in your eyes, you're determined.
		Tell you what, bring me the hearts of ten Bloodsuckers, and I'll tell you how to find them... at least you will have experience facing these devils... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_20">
		<text>I will not disappoint you! Consider it done</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_21">
		<text>Be careful out there young Stalker! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_22">
		<text>Yes, I'm glad you're seeing reason.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_23">
		<text>Well said, let's turn our minds to more pleasant things.</text>
	</string>

<string id="forester_legendary_1_0">
		<text>About Vlad and Drakul. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_1">
		<text>What is it? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_2">
		<text>I want to hunt them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_3">
		<text>Tell me the story again how you first met them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_4">
		<text>Tell me the story again how you shot Moloch.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_5">
		<text>It was not long after the second great explosion, the one which created this hell. 
			I picked up a distress radio call of survivors - a military scout squad which got lost in the Zaton swamps. Apparently their commander walked into a Vortex and with him their only map got shredded. 
			Imagine giving only one map for a whole squad - but it seems some things didn't change since the old days. Nevertheless, I found the two survivors and promised to lead them back to their headquarters - back in the days the Military still had a presence in the Army Warehouses.
			We reached this forest at dusk - I wanted to overnight at this complex, but these boys were eager to rejoin their base. Nowadays, crossing the forest at night would mean certain death, but you know back then most of these mutants were quite rare and didn't yet reach the southern parts of the Zone. 
			So we made a compromise - we were to take a rest and have something to eat and continue our journey after having warmed our bellies with food and our spirit with vodka. We entered the forest to gather some firewood and cooked some meat on a clearing. I don't know what attracted them - the smell of food or maybe the laughter...
			I left the fireplace to take a piss while the two soldiers continued fooling around. When returned to the fire I saw one of them lying on the ground - hissing from laughter I thought... it was only when I stood next to him that I noticed the blood gurgling out of his throat. I looked up - the other stood there with wide eyes and behind him...
			I don't know which of the brothers it was, but that was the first Bloodsucker I saw in my life. I didn't understand - I simply froze. That's when I felt tentacles grapling around my neck - strong and hot was that grip! I wasn't thinking - I grabbed a piece of burning wood and struck behind me! 
			The Bloodsucker immediately let go of me, and I scrambled off, running for my life! That's how I met Moloch, Vlad and Drakul!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_6">
		<text>I started to track the brothers, gather informations on this new danger lurking in my wood. I tried to lay traps - the first worked but I wasn't able to capitalise on it, but the brothers also learned and started to avoid them.
			Sometimes I managed to wound one - sometimes they managed to wound me. I tried to find their lair by following their foodsteps - to no avail, I never found the exact location. This continued until one day, some bandits tried to jump me. They tried to extort me - I refused. It escalated and they ended up dead - except one! He was wounded and out cold - bleeding to death. 
			So I decided not to let a good corpse go to waste and I carried him into the forest as bait. I tied him to a tree and waited in ambush for the brothers. And sure enough they came - surrounding that poor fellow. Yes, it was not right for me to do that to a fellow man - to expose him to such horros without giving him a fighting chance... But back then I thought it was a good idea.
			While they were gulping on their easy prey, I took aim and patiently waiting for my shot. And I shot - it went right through Moloch's heart. Vlad and Drakul screached up in fright and took off - and I took my trophy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_7">
		<text>[Bloodsucker Hearts] I brought proof that I'm able to hunt Bloodsuckers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_8">
		<text>I killed Gullinbursti! And Vlad and Drakul will meet the same fate if you tell me where to find them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_9">
		<text>Impressive... I'm reluctant to tell you this, but I believe a promise is a promise... So listen carefully - their lair is deep in the forest to the east of here - in the proximity of an old soviet tank. Where exactly - I don't know but that doesn't matter.
			You will have to bait them out, and I believe to know how to do it but you won't like it... You will have to adone my old overcoat - it's the one I had while I was hunting them in the old days, it will have my smell and they will believe that it's me who dares to meet them. 
			It's old - so don't expect good protection... I did some repairs and added two fasteners so you can use two attachments - so choose wisely! And of course you will have to do it during the night, when they feel confident in the protection the dark provides - else they will not dare to affront "me"...
			\n \nAre you still up to it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_10">
		<text>Impressive... I might have underestimated your skill and experience! I'm reluctant to tell you this, but you might be ready... Alright, so listen carefully - their lair is deep in the forest to the east of here - in the proximity of an old soviet tank. Where exactly - I don't know but that doesn't matter.
			You will have to bait them out, and I believe to know how to do it but you won't like it... You will have to adone my old overcoat - it's the one I had while I was hunting them in the old days, it will have my smell and they will believe that it's me who dares to meet them. 
			It's old - so don't expect good protection... I did some repairs and added two fasteners so you can use two attachments - so choose wisely! And of course you will have to do it during the night, when they feel confident in the protection the dark provides - else they will not dare to affront "me"...
			\n \nAre you still up to it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_11">
		<text>I believe that is enough.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_23">
		<text>Yes, I still am.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_24">
		<text>To be honest I have to think about it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_25">
		<text>Alright, then come see me the night you want to set out - shortly after sunset. Prepare for a prolonged battle, it's very likely that you will have to affront their brethren too! Stock up on shells, medecine and so on. Don't underestimate this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_26">
		<text>There is no shame in being afraid of mortal danger! Take your time to think about it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_27">
		<text>Alright, let's talk about something else.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
<string id="forester_legendary_2_0">
		<text>About the hunt for Vlad and Drakul. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_1">
		<text>What is it? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_2">
		<text>I am ready for the hunt.</text>
	</string>
<string id="forester_legendary_2_3">
		<text>I am ready for the hunt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_4">
		<text>I need more time.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_5">
		<text>Can you tell me about the plan again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_6">
		<text>Sure, listen carefully: You will have to do it during the night, when they feel confident in the protection the dark provides. Their lair is deep in the forest to the east of here - in the proximity of an old soviet tank. Where exactly - I don't know but that doesn't matter.
			You will have to bait them out, and I believe to know how to do it but you won't like it... You will have to adone my old overcoat - it's the one I had while I was hunting them in the old days, it will have my smell and they will believe that it's me who dares to meet them. 
			It's old - so don't expect good protection... I did some repairs and added two fasteners so you can use two attachments - so choose wisely! And I have the strong suspicion that you will not only have to face them, but their brethren too!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_7">
		<text>Alright, I see you're adamant. Here is the coat - you will not have to wear it on your way there, but try to put it on shortly before reaching the tank. Do you remember the way? It's deep in the forest, 
		east of here, but to reach it you have to pass through an old mine tunnel a bit to the south. After passing it you turn north again an you walk for quite some time. The tank is hidden by a small hill - ready yourself there and approach the tank carefully.
		I'm not sure how they will react, but maybe they will send some of their brethren first to tire you out. Remember - you have to do it by night! If the sun rises, they will retreat. You will need to set out shortly after sunset...\n \nNow good luck young Stalker - may the night be in your favour.</text>
	</string>
<string id="forester_legendary_2_8">
		<text>Very good. Come see me after shortly after sunset - I'll give you the coat then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_9">
		<text>No problem - you know you don't have to do this. Let's talk about something else.</text>
	</string>	

<string id="forester_legendary_3_0">
		<text>Are there other named mutants?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_1">
		<text>Yes there are... there is Gullinbursti - the Boar. Butcher named him, that boar is the scurge of any hunter in the Great Swamp region. Then there is Moby Dick - the white Pseudogiant. Gonta is intimately acquainted to him. Finally there is Chyort - the Chimera male.
			Evasive fucker - the only known survivor is Trapper.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_2">
		<text>Tell me more about Gullinbursti.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_3">
		<text>Tell me more about Moby Dick.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_4">
		<text>Tell me more about Chyort.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_5">
		<text>Thank you for these informations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_6">
		<text>He's the patron saint of any boar in the Great Swamp - many hunters are known to have died by his tusks when they hunted for his brethren. His skin is said to be as thick as the skull of [...]. Butcher tried to hunt him in the past - according to him he met that beast twice - and twice that boar shrugged off a shotgun blast to the flank!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_7">
		<text>Moby Dick - Gonta's nemesis. He carries that name because he's large as a whale - and an albino! That Pseudogiant killed his childhood friend, and since then Gonta is hunting him, and for years he eluded his vengeance. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_8">
		<text>Yes, Chyort... the devil himself. They say one strike would be enough to even cleave Sidorovich in half! Not that I ever met Sidorovich, but according to the rumors, it sounds like quite a feat! No one knows where his lair is, but he sometimes wanders into different regions to either eat or procreate! 
		Trapper says that the stronger Chimeras are his offspring - considering the amount of strong chimeras, you can imagine that Chyort's hunger for flesh is only surpassed by sexual appetite.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_10">
		<text>No problem, I hope this will serve as a cautionary tale - don't fuck with these mutants!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="forester_legendary_4_0">
		<text>I didn't manage to kill the Bloodsucker in time - dawn was upon me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_4_1">
		<text>Don't worry young Stalker, the most important is that you're still alive! You will have another chance another night. Come see me if you wish to give it another shot.</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="forester_legendary_5_0">
		<text>Good news! Vlad and Drakul won't hunt these forests anymore!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_5_1">
		<text>Excellent! Great work! You did a great deed tonight! Let's drink to your accomplishment!</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="st_forester_legendary_1_info">
		<text>Forester: You are getting close to their hunting spot. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_forester_legendary_2_info">
		<text>Forester: My wounds start aching again, Vlad and Drakul are coming out of their hiding. Good luck Stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_forester_legendary_3_info">
		<text>Forester: You  managed to kill the younger Bloodsuckers, but the sun is already rising and Vlad and Drakul will not dare to fight during the day. You will have to try another time. Come see me.</text>
	</string>
	
---- Doctor Alyosha Karmov ----	
	
<string id="st_karmov_trouble_1_info">
		<text>Alyosha Karmov: Emergency! I request help of any nearby Stalker. I'm Doctor Alyosha Karmov - I'm surrounded by a horde of Snorks in the Agroprom Train tunnel. I request emergency extradition by any nearby Stalker.</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_karmov_trouble_2_info">
		<text>Alyosha Karmov: This is an Emergency! I request urgent help. I'm Doctor Alyosha Karmov - I'm surrounded by a horde of Snorks in the Agroprom Train tunnel. Please, they are getting closer.</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_karmov_trouble_3_info">
		<text>Alyosha Karmov: I'm Doctor Alyosha Karmov - I'm surrounded by a horde of Snorks in the Agroprom Train tunnel. Make haste - they have trapped me!</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_0">
		<text>A-a-are they gone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Who?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_2">
		<text>The Snorks of course!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_3">
		<text>I guess so - I only saw a couple at the entrance, but I have no idea where the others went.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Ah, I must have scarred them off! You're welcome!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Right... Are you Alyosha?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Doctor Alyosha Karmov - for you Doctor Karmov - proper etiquette has to be kept after all, even in such a forsaken place like this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_7">
		<text>Alright ... Doctor Karmov, what are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Whatever Alyosha, what are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_9">
		<text>I was on an expedition for Sakharov - gathering mutant samples. We are scientists after all. Suddenly I heard a terrible screech and I turned around - a horde of Snorks! I immediately retreated into the tunnel to fend them off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_10">
		<text>I will allow these familiarities, considering we fought together and forged a bond in blood together. 
			I was on an expedition for Sakharov - gathering mutant samples. We are scientists after all. Suddenly I heard a terrible screech and I turned around - a horde of Snorks! I immediately retreated into the tunnel to fend them off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Hmm, alright. What would you consider to be an appropriate reward for my troubles?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_12">
		<text>For your troubles? You just said that there were no Snorks outsides!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_13">
		<text>Ah I see. I'll be on my way then, I lost enough time with you - good luck with your mutant samples.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_14">
		<text>What the fuck? You were begging on the channels for help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_15">
		<text>Wait! Considering your altruistic - although unrequired - inclination to help me, I will return the favor!
				I'll be escorting you back to the Agroprom Factories!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_16">
		<text>Begging for help? Me? I protest: I was calmly updating the other Stalkers on my situation - like any professional would do.
			\n \nBut you're right, considering your altruistic - although unrequired - inclination to help me, I will return the favor!
			I'll be escorting you back to the Agroprom Factories!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_17">
		<text>Ehm, that's kind of you, but I don't need to go there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_18">
		<text>Alright, I wanted to go there either way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_19">
		<text>I insist! The Zone is dangerous out there - you'll be safer with my trusted Nosrog and Scar as your companions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_20">
		<text>I see... well then let's get going, I don't have all day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_start_dialog_21">
		<text>Excellent! Lead the way!</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_0_0">
		<text>Seems that we arrived.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_karmov_0_1">
		<text>Thanks mate</text>
	</string>

	
--- Vybegallo and the Scientists---

--Quest 1--

- Vybegallo-

<string id="vybegallo_start_0">
		<text>What to you want? I'm busy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_1">
		<text>Greetings Vybegallo. I got your Tuna Bag.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_2">
		<text>Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_3">
		<text>Then might I ask you to not stand in the way of science?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_111">
		<text>Ah marvelous! Thank you mon cher! Science will not forget your contribution to progress! I believe a reward is in order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_112">
		<text>Thanks. Why is that much tuna important to science?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_113">
		<text>Thanks. I'll be on my way then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_114">
		<text>That's food for my satis... no that doesn't concern you, mon cher. But yes ... maybe you can help me out? You work with Butcher, right? So you must be a hunter too...
		Well, very well... you can be discrete, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_115">
		<text>Yes, yes ... ah wait, wait mon cher! Maybe you can help me out? You work with Butcher, right? So you must be a hunter too...
		Well, very well... you can be discrete, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_4">
		<text>Ah yes, so you work with Butcher? Well, very well... you can be discrete, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_5">
		<text>Yes of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_6">
		<text>I don't like the direction this is going. What do you want?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_7">
		<text>Excellent! You see mon cher, I need a sample from a Pseudogiant - for scientific reasons of course! For the sake of progress, mon cher. Doesn't matter what, a hand, and eye, it's hide. Bring it to me and I'll compensate you for your troubles. Deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_8">
		<text>Mon cher, why this attitude? I'm a scientist, a man dedicated to science! I need a sample from a Pseudogiant - for strictly scientific reasons of course! For the sake of progress, mon cher. Doesn't matter what, a hand, and eye, it's hide. Bring it to me and I'll compensate you for your troubles.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_9">
		<text>Alright, I see what I can do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_10">
		<text>I don't know, I have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_11">
		<text>Perfect!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_12">
		<text>Think, but don't take too long, time is of an essence for me!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="vybegallo_time_0">
		<text>Concerning that job.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="vybegallo_time_1">
		<text>Oui mon cher, will you help science out?</text>
	</string>	


<string id="vybegallo_2_0">
		<text>About your pseudogiant body part.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_1">
		<text>Oui mon cher? Did you find something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_2">
		<text>I found a pseudogiant eye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_3">
		<text>I found a pseudogiant hand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_4">
		<text>I found a pseudogiant hide.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_5">
		<text>No I didn't find anything yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_6">
		<text>What are you waiting for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_7">
		<text>This is marvellous, mon cher! Your contribution to science will not be forgotten! Here take this, for your troubles!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_8">
		<text>I've talked to your collegues Vybegallo. This letter is for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_9">
		<text>Wha-what? What did you do? What did you tell them? What is this??? \n \n...\n \nHow dare he! The tsarist gendarmerie did not frighten me, and Sakharov will not frighten me!! \n \n And you, you traitor!!! You rat!!! Out of my sight!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_10">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>

<string id="vybegallo_3_0">
		<text>You wanted to see me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_1">
		<text>Yes mon cher, we... we have a problem. My experiment was on the way to become a tremendous success, oui mon cher, truly a scientific revolution! But...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_2">
		<text>...but?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_3">
		<text>But he's not there anymore! I went down to check upon him, and he's gone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_4">
		<text>"He"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_5">
		<text>What happened, did someone steal your experiment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_6">
		<text>Yes, the Partially Satisfied Man - the necessary intermediary to the Fully Satisfied Man! Ah, imagine a man who is able to satisfy all his needs by himself! 
		Wouldn't that be a scientific marvel mon cher? \n \n And now he's gone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_7">
		<text>An eventuality which should not be ruled out, but... I rather believe he broke out... Maybe I didn't give him enough food?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_8">
		<text>Broke out? How is that possible?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_9">
		<text>How it is possible? By being a colossal scientific success mon cher, that's how it is possible!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_10">
		<text>Is "he" dangerous?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_11">
		<text>Barely mon cher, barely. But we cannot allow him to run off, that would attract unwarranted attention... n'est-ce pas?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_12">
		<text>What exactly is "he"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_13">
		<text>The Partially Satisfied Man, mon cher! You need to pay attention when I'm telling you about this!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_14">
		<text>No I mean, what is he really? What does he look like?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_15">
		<text>Difficult to say, I never saw him after he hatched... He should probably resemble me, as he has part of my DNA? But these are details mon cher, don't bother about it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_16">
		<text>What do you want me to do about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_17">
		<text>Mon cher, it's with a heavy heart that I have to ask you to liquidate my experiment. 
			What a shame, what a loss for science! But we cannot allow him to run off - that would only attract unnecessary attention to my experiments!
			You wouldn't believe how reactionary some of my collegues are. But at least I should be able to gather his remains in order to conduct further experiments - progress cannot be stopped, n'est-ce pas mon cher?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_18">
		<text>Where can I find "him"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_19">
		<text>He should still be somewhere in the Underground.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_20">
		<text>What is the pay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_21">
		<text>Always so materialistic! But yes, don't worry about the pay - it will be more than enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_22">
		<text>Alright, I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_23">
		<text>I have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_24">
		<text>Excellent mon cher, excellent! Make your preparations and come see me before setting off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_25">
		<text>Then hurry up mon cher, time is running out!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="vybegallo_4_0">
		<text>About your "experiment".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_4_1">
		<text>What is it, mon cher?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_4_2">
		<text>I'm ready to set out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_4_3">
		<text>I need more time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_4_4">
		<text>Excellent! Don't make him suffer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_4_5">
		<text>Then hurry up mon cher, time is running out!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="vybegallo_5_0">
		<text>I killed your "experiment".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_1">
		<text>Marvellous, excellent work mon cher!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_2">
		<text>You didn't fucking tell me that you were breeding a fucking Pseudogiant!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_3">
		<text>Ah very interesting, so the Pseudogiant DNA took the overhand? This is extraordinary! It was only supposed to improve his resilience in this climate, but the Pseudogiant took completely over?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_4">
		<text>What the fuck are you doing? There are enough dangers in the Zone - why are you creating new ones?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_5">
		<text>Mon cher, this is scientific progress! Some risks have to be taken! Marie Curie took risks for humankind - Yuri Gagarin too! The list is long, mon cher! Now we know more, and we won't repeat the mistakes! Consider it a scientific success!
			But I see that you're new to the scientific method - and I believe that I owe you a reward. Take this! I... borrowed it from the institute after a disagreement. It's a prototype - but I believe it should be quite useful to... more practical oriented people. Thank you very much mon cher!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_6">
		<text>Yes, now please give me the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_7">
		<text>Straight to the point as always. Alright, here are the funds. Enjoy - and thank you for helping me... cover up this incident!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_8">
		<text>Fuck you - don't contact me again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_9">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>		



	
-the others-
<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_0">
		<text>Do you know a fellow scientist called "Vybegallo"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_1">
		<text>Vybegallo? Well, yes I know him… is there something with him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_2">
		<text>No, I only met him recently.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_3">
		<text>Okay… did he tell you something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_4">
		<text>No, we barely spoke.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_5">
		<text>Alright… Please tell me if you know something about what he is up to. He himself is not dangerous, but his scientific research on the other hand… My advice to you, don’t get caught up in his dealings.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_6">
		<text>He asked me to help him with his science experiment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_7">
		<text>He asked you for help? No offence, but you don’t look like a lab assistant. Why would Vybegallo need a Stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_8">
		<text>He asked me to find some artifact for him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_9">
		<text>An artifact? This seems unusual for him, but maybe he finally found a normal research topic…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_10">
		<text>He asked me to find some pseudogiant part for him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_11">
		<text>What? This is horrible!!! \n \n… \n \nYou see, years ago Vybegallo got into his head to create the “ideal man” – or the “fully satisfied man” as he calls it, but his experiments were one disaster after another. I'm not talking about the ethical aspects, my god, although they are bad enough. His first version, the fully unsatisfied man, was a miserable creature who dwindled away under our very eyes... But Vybegallo was not discouraged and continued his experiments.
		\n \nAfter one especially egregious attempt which nearly cost the life of half his department, his research institute kicked him out. But Vybegallo somehow managed to pull some strings and wound up here! I’m afraid he didn’t give up on this experiment… Who knows what he will unleash?  \n \nI implore you, don’t help him out! \n \n No this is not enough, here take this order to him and make him understand that he has to cease any dangerous experiments immediately. I don’t know how much he promised you, I can’t put much on the table at the moment, but I will find some reward. \n\nWill you help us out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_12">
		<text>Sure, I will deliver the letter and not help him out any further.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_13">
		<text>No deal, I honour my contracts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_14">
		<text>Thanks I appreciate it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_15">
		<text>You fool.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_0">
		<text>I brought the order to Vybegallo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_1">
		<text>And? How did he take it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_2">
		<text>Not very well, he screamed something about the tsarist gendarmerie and that you won't frighten him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_3">
		<text>I feared as much... Nevertheless thanks for your help, here your reward: it's not much but I hope it can help you out there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_4">
		<text>What will you do about Vybegallo?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_5">
		<text>I don't know, I have to council with the director... \n \nIn the meantime I'll send a global message to everyone that Sakharov is under sanction and that whoever trades in mutant parts with him will be excluded from any business with us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_6">
		<text>Sanctioned? Does that work here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_7">
		<text>To be honest, no. The largest traders will maybe refrein from doing business with him, but individual Stalkers don't give a shit about sanctions. But we have to do something, and it will make at least some people think twice about working with him.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="st_sakharov_vybegallo_1_info">
		<text>Attention! Important announcement: \n \nThe scientist Amvrosiy Vybegallo is under sanction! \n \nAnyone who is caught trading with him in mutant parts will be sanctioned too!</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_0">
		<text>I found this in the mercenary base in Zaton. [Pseudogiant parts order]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_1">
		<text>What is it? \n \n...\n \nThat shit head. \n \nListen to me; what I tell you now is off the record, noone will acknowledge this: I talked to the director and he agrees with me, Vybegallo has to stopped By.All.Means! He sanctioned the liquidation of Vybegallo if he continues his dangerous experiment. Well this is it! 
		I ask you - no I insist: kill Vybegallo. He cannot continue doing his experiments. \n \nI understand that you are a Stalker and won't do it for free. We have prototypes here, and I'm willing to let one fall of the truck for you. So what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_2">
		<text>Amvrosiy Vybegallo will sleep with the snorks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_3">
		<text>No way, I am not an assassin.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_4">
		<text>Thank you. Remember, we never had this conversation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_5">
		<text>I understand. Remember, we never had this conversation.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_4_0">
		<text>Vybegallo is no more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_4_1">
		<text>I don't know what you're talking about.</text>
	</string>	

<string id="st_vybegallo_help_satisfied_man_info">
		<text>Vybegallo: Mon cher, we might have a problem on our hands... Can you come urgently?</text>
	</string>	
	
	
	
---- Sidorovich----
<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_0">
		<text>I need some money Sidorovich, do you have a better paying job to offer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_1">
		<text>You’re in luck, I’m indeed hiring some guns at the moment… I’m putting together a team to take back the railway bridge crossing. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_2">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_3">
		<text>The bandits recently reinforced that crossing and are asking for quite a high bribe to let people pass – very bad for business. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_4">
		<text>An assault? What’s the plan?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_5">
		<text>We will effectuate a pincer movement. Cold send a squad over to help out, under the leadership of a certain “Rodion Oslyabya”, they should arrive soon at the northern farm. 
		My team will gather at the mill under the leadership of Alexander Peresvet. \n\nYou will take on the role of messenger – you’ll first need to bypass the railway bridge to make contact with Rodion and check if they are ready for the assault. 
		If they are ready, you return to the Mill where Rodion will wait. If everyone is in place, tell Rodion that the assault can begin. \n\nAny questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_6">
		<text>Why do I need to make contact in person. Can’t we use the PDA messenger to communicate with the Clear Sky squad?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_7">
		<text>Are you aware that to render PDA communication secure is a complicated procedure? You would have to exchange encryption and decryption keys manually - a huge hazzle. 
		Surprise is primordial in this assault – the PDA stays silent until the very moment the assault begins. \n\nAny other questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_8">
		<text>How do I bypass the railway bridge unseen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_9">
		<text>You really are a rookie… well there is a small underway to the west of the bridge and the mill. It’s small, badly lit and a little dangerous but will suit our needs perfectly. \n\nAny other questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_10">
		<text>How much are you willing to pay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_11">
		<text>Considering that you are a rookie, you get a rookies pay. \n\nAny other question?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_12">
		<text>About the plan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_13">
		<text>Yes, do you have any questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_14">
		<text>Can you tell me the plan again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_15">
		<text>What about the vehicle park to the east of the bridge? Won’t the bandits come in reinforcement?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_16">
		<text>That is very possible, and the reason why the assault has to be over as quick as possible. If the bandits send reinforcement, you beat them off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_17">
		<text>Can we not make a diversionary attack on the vehicle park?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_18">
		<text>I like that idea, but we don’t have enough manpower to make such an attack. The plan stays, we overwhelm the bridge defences and dig in our heels if they send reinforcement.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_19">
		<text>What if I take on the vehicle park by myself?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_20">
		<text>Damn dude, did you watch too many movies? This is not Rambo! But if you really want to prove yourself, be my guest. \n\nAny other questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_21">
		<text>No other questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_22">
		<text>Alright, so what do you say? Are you in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_23">
		<text>I’m in!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_24">
		<text>I need some time to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_25">
		<text>I have some more questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_26">
		<text>Alright, better now than later. Ask away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_27">
		<text>Alright! Gear up, and come see me if you’re ready!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_28">
		<text>Alright. Think about it, but hurry, Clear Sky is on their way.</text>
	</string>

<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_0">
		<text>About the Railway Bridge assault.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_1">
		<text>Yes, tell me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_2">
		<text>I am ready. Tell me what to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_3">
		<text>I am ready. I'll take part in the main assault.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_4">
		<text>I am ready. I'll make the diversionary attack on the vehicle park.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_5">
		<text>I need more time. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_6">
		<text>Alright. Let me remind you of your task so you don't fuck it up. You are to bypass the bandit forces and establish contact with Rodion Oslyabya, the leader of the Clear Sky forces, in the northern village.
			If he's there, you're to return back to the mill and report to Alexander Peresvet, my guy. If everything is in place, you're to take part in the assault. \n \nEverything clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_7">
		<text>Alright. Let me remind you of your task so you don't fuck it up. You are to bypass the bandit forces and establish contact with Rodion Oslyabya, the leader of the Clear Sky forces, in the northern village.
			If he's there, you're to return back to the mill and report to Alexander Peresvet, my guy. If everything is in place, you're to take part in the assault. \n \nEverything clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_8">
		<text>Are you sure? If that's how you want it, be my guest. It certainly will help the assault. I'll tell Alexander to send someone else to establish contact with Clear Sky. Is everything else clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_9">
		<text>Alright, but get moving, we don't have much time left! Remember, suprise is of essence!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_10">
		<text>Everything clear. I'm on my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_11">
		<text>Wait! I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_12">
		<text>Better now than later. What is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_14">
		<text>About the plan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_15">
		<text>What is it?</text>
	</string>

<string id="sidorovich_railway_3_0">
		<text>The assault has been a success, the railway is ours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_3_1">
		<text>Good job! That checkpoint is of tremendous importance for our safety and our local economy. You deserve your reward Stalker! Here! 
			I recommend you to spend it here, to support your local business. I got tremendous deals for you, have a look!</text>
	</string>
<string id="sidorovich_railway_4_0">
		<text>The assault has been a success, the railway is ours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_4_1">
		<text>Good job! Your diversionary attack was indeed of great help! Now that the checkpoint is ours, our safety and that of our local economy is guarded. You deserve your reward Stalker! Here! 
			I recommend you to spend it here, to support your local business. I got tremendous deals for you, have a look!</text>
	</string>



<string id="st_assault_railway_info_1">
		<text>Let's fuck those bandits up! URRRAAAAAAAA!!!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_assault_railway_info_2">
		<text>URRRAAAAAAAA!!!!!</text>
	</string>


<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Get lost Stalker, we're occupied.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Are you the guys Cold send in order to assault the railway bridge?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Yes we are - and you're the messenger? As you can see we're ready, I hope you guys too. So tell me, can we begin, can we get this over with?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Yeah, I'll join up with the guys on the other side and we'll give the sign.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Alright, we'll be waiting.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_1_0">
		<text>What a fight, I'm glad you made it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_1_1">
		<text>Yeah, that was quite tough. Thanks for the help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_1_2">
		<text>What are you going to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_1_3">
		<text>I have orders to guard this checkpoint.</text>
	</string>

<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_1">
		<text>I am the guy Sidorovich sent as a messenger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Good. Is the Clear Sky squad in place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_3">
		<text>They are. When does the rest of our guys arrive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_4">
		<text>This is all there is. Sidorovich tends to be “frugal” in his hiring.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Fuck. At least the guys from Clear Sky came prepared…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Yeah those guys are reliable. Let us hope we will catch these banditfuckers with their pants down. The plan is easy; we approach – throw our grenades and assault. Are you ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_7">
		<text>Yes I’m ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Grenades? I don’t have any…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_9">
		<text>Shit mate, who comes to an assault without grenades? Here take this one – pay me a drink when we survived this bullshit. \n\nWell, enough chatting, we have to earn our pay now. Ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_10">
		<text>Let’s go!</text>
	</string>

<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_1_0">
		<text>What a fight! We made it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_1_1">
		<text>Yeah mate, that was crazy! I'm glad to see you made it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_1_2">
		<text>Yeah man, I'm glad to see you to! What will you do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_1_3">
		<text>I'll stay here and guard the passage.</text>
	</string>

<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_0">
		<text>Hey mate, I wanted to thank you for the grenade you gave me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_1">
		<text>No problem, I'm sure the bandits would disagree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_2">
		<text>[Zone Vodka] Here, this is for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_3">
		<text>[Nemiroff] Here, this is for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_4">
		<text>[Putinka] Here, this is for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_8">
		<text>[Stolichnaya] Here, this is for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_5">
		<text>Wait, I'll get a drink to thank you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_6">
		<text>That's mighty cool of you to remember, I will remember this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_7">
		<text>No problem mate.</text>
	</string>

---- Market Share----
<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Yo, what's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_1">
		<text>I got your message. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Ah, you're the Stalker who disabled the Brainscorcher?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_4">
		<text>I am, what is it to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Who is asking?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Me and my man Chris over there followed your work, and we are fans of your work ethic. We want to propose a collab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_7">
		<text>Not of the trusting kind are you? Don’t worry, I get you, distrust makes you live longer.
		\n \nKnow what? Have a drink on us in the station and ask about Marlo Stanfield and Chris Partlow - people will fill you in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_8">
		<text>A collab? What is the goal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_9">
		<text>The goal is money and renown of course - what else is there to be wanted? The way to achieve it? That's the juicy part.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_10">
		<text>I've never heard of you - why should we work together?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Haven't heard of me yet you mean. Don't worry, that will change. 
		\n \nKnow what? Have a drink on us in the station and ask about Marlo Stanfield and Chris Partlow - people will fill you in.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	
<string id="chris_partlow_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Yo, talk to my man Marlo first.</text>
	</string>
	



<string id="hawaiian_about_marlo_0">
		<text>Do you know some Stalkers by the name of “Marlo Stanfield” and “Chris Partlow”?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_about_marlo_1">
		<text>I do... some serious guys, made a name for themselves two years ago. Violent guys too - and that means something here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_about_marlo_2">
		<text>Can you be more specific about them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_about_marlo_3">
		<text>I only saw them a couple of times when they passed through so I didn't have any close dealings with them, but I heard some stories. I assume that 
		they started off like normal guys - bribed their way past the checkpoint and started to do some minor work here and there. The first time their name rang out was two years ago, some bandits were making trouble in Zaton and 
		Sidorovich recruited them amongst others to put them back in place. Story goes that there was a traitor amongst the group which lead them into an ambush - those who weren't killed were taken as hostage. 
		Marlo and Chris [FINISH STORY]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_about_marlo_4">
		<text>Can you tell me something about them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_about_marlo_5">
		<text>Are they reliable? </text>
	</string>


<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_1">
		<text>I asked around about you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_2">
		<text>And, did you like what you were hearing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_3">
		<text>Depends. What is your proposition?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_4">
		<text>Not really, you sound like brutes. I'm not interested in working with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_5">
		<text>We are not that different you and us. We are always working for someone else and his pockets - yes we get paid but in the end it's them who are profiting from our work, it's them who gain in influence and importance. 
			If you're someone's dog - you'll always be a dog. A fierce dog maybe, even a feared one, but there's no respect for the dog himself - only for the dog's owner. I don't know about you, but I've had enough. That's the reason why we propose you a joint-venture. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_6">
		<text>I'm all ears.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_7">
		<text>I've got no problems with working for other people.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_8">
		<text>Aight. First, how do you feel about Sidorovich?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_9">
		<text>Sidorovich? Fuck that greedy pig – the guy got rich by scamming rookies and leeching off the misery in the Zone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_10">
		<text>Sidorovich? He is businessman – buying low selling high, profiting from people if it so happens. A by-product of the Zone, I got no problems with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_11">
		<text>Sidorovich? I like him, why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_12">
		<text>Very well. So I believe you will not have any qualms about taking over his business?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_13">
		<text>Yeah, here the strong eat the weak, and Sidorovich knows it. What he doesn't know is that his turn has come too - he grew too complacent, too comfortable in his little damp bunker.
		When was the last time that fat fuck went outside? Who knows - his </text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_14">
		<text>You like Sidorovich? What, are you his bitch?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_15">
		<text>Taking over his business? What do you mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_16">
		<text>I like the sound of it - what do you have in mind?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_17">
		<text>You like Sidorovich? What, are you his bitch?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_18">
		<text>Taking over his business? What do you mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_0_19">
		<text>I like the sound of it - what do you have in mind?</text>
	</string>




---- Quest 1 -----
<string id="chris_partlow_1_0">
		<text>How do we get started?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_1_1">
		<text>Your target is an officer called "Harald Virtanen". He is stationed at the Zaton Waste Processing Station: you have to kill him and steal his PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_1_2">
		<text>How should I do that? There are at least a dozen of heavily armed mercenaries stationed at that place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_1_3">
		<text>Don't worry - we already have a plan. It's no coincidence that Harald is our target - it seems that the guy is an alcoholic and sneaks out during night to get his buzz.
	His favourite drinking spot is a garage in the south east corner of the compound. Sneak up on him and kill him - remember to take his PDA too! That will trigger the procedure.
	And while you're at it - if you still haven't found a mercenary outfit, maybe you can also "borrow" his - he won't need it anymore.
	\n \nAre you ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_1_4">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_1_5">
		<text>No, I will need some time preparing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_1_6">
		<text>Alright - remember to take his PDA or else everything will be for nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_1_7">
		<text>Alright - make your preparations.</text>
	</string>

<string id="chris_partlow_2_0">
		<text>I got the PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_2_1">
		<text>Well done! Now we have to wait - I will send you a message when they are doing their move. In the meantime take a rest and get ready for the next stage: repair your costume and stock up on ammo. Here, I managed to get you a repair kit for a light outfit and a gun.</text>
	</string>


<string id="zaton_mercenary_1_start_dialog_0">
		<text>What do you want? Can't you see I'm occupied?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zaton_mercenary_1_start_dialog_1">
			<text>Marlo and Chris say hello.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="zaton_mercenary_1_start_dialog_2">
			<text>What the fuck are you talking about?</text>
		</string>
		<string id="zaton_mercenary_1_start_dialog_3">
			<text>...</text>
	</string>

--- Quest 2 part 1 ----


<string id="st_zaton_mercenary_courrier_deathrattle_info">
		<text>Jan Baran: Urgent Stalker ambushed usweareattackkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkk</text>
	</string>

<string id="chris_partlow_3_0">
		<text>Are the courriers on their way?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_3_1">
		<text>They are: they left their base yesterday and travelled from Limansk to Yanov using their secret path. They should arrive soon and will look for a place to camp overnight - that's when you will strike.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_3_2">
		<text>Do you know where they will camp?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_3_3">
		<text>No, we were not able to find out their plans. It should be somewhere close to where their path emerges, somewhere around the Bandit camp in the South-West. It won't be in the open, so look for any buildings or structures giving shelter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_3_4">
		<text>Why don't they stay at the bandit camp over night?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_3_5">
		<text>Would you sleep with a dozen gopniks around you? That's unnecessary trouble - you don't know if you're going to wake up with all your money - or teeths.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_3_6">
		<text>Alright - I will be on my way then.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="chris_partlow_4_0">
		<text>Yo Chris, I got the USB. Here, make a copy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chris_partlow_4_1">
		<text>Excellent work! Alright, let me make a copy \n \n...\n \nHere, take the USB. Now deliver it to an officer called "Aivar Kuusk". He should be somwhere inside the Waste Processing Station. \n \n
		Don't forget your Mercenary suit! Remember: no stupid movement like running or jumping - and don't wave your weapon around! I hope your suit and helmet are repaired - and don't forget to take a weapon with you which is used by these assholes. Go in, deliver the USB and get out. </text>
	</string>

--- Quest 2 part 2 ----

<string id="zaton_mercenary_2_start_dialog_0">
		<text>What do you want? Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zaton_mercenary_2_start_dialog_1">
			<text>I am the courrier - I bring you your USB stick with the encryption and decryption key for this section.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="zaton_mercenary_2_start_dialog_2">
			<text>Ah yes, thanks.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="zaton_mercenary_2_start_dialog_3">
			<text>...</text>
	</string>


<string id="jupiter_monk_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Yo you're Marlo's guy. What's the word, are we crashing their party?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jupiter_monk_start_dialog_1">
			<text>Yeah, we can go.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="jupiter_monk_start_dialog_2">
			<text>Wait, I'll be back shortly.</text>
		</string>
		<string id="jupiter_monk_start_dialog_3">
			<text>Alright men, let's roll out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jupiter_monk_start_dialog_4">
			<text>...</text>
	</string>
----Stage 4----
---Takeover---
--Marlo--

<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_0">
		<text>So, what is the next stage in your plan?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_1">
		<text>Now my friend we take over the Skadovsk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_2">
		<text>The Skadovsk? Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_3">
		<text>The Skadovsk is the key to the north - most Loners here sell and buy from Beard and Owl. Until now Sidorovich and Beard had a deal: Beard, and with him the Skadovsk, trade with Sidorovich - he gets the artifacts and they get weapons, money and men in exchange.
	If we own the Skadovsk, the north belongs to us - and Sidorovich will lose a huge source of financial revenues thus weakening his position. And what is most important - it's ripe for the taking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_4">
		<text>How do you plan to take it over?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_5">
		<text>You see, Beard is under a lot of pressure - Monolith activities are growing and their raids become more frequent. He can only protect with difficulty the Stalkers there and people are getting restless.
	Sidorovich on the other hands tries to cheap out on support - he only sends the bare minimum citing difficult supply lines as an excuse. 
	If we increase their difficulties, the support for Beard and Sidorovich will drop and we swoop in offering protection and supplies taking the Skadovsk for us - Beard will have no choice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_6">
		<text>How do you know all of this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_7">
		<text>We already made a proposition to Owl to co-op - let's say he's quite enthusiastic about this takeover. He told us about the weak points we can exploit - he's also your main contact partner during this operation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_8">
		<text>How do you plan on increasing the pressure on Beard?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_9">
		<text>Beard mostly relies on two Stalkers for protecting the Skadovsk: Spartacus and Achilles. Both of them are fearsome warriors and they enjoy the popularity and support of many Loners in the north . men who are ready to fight with them.
	If both of them die, Beard will have lost most of his military powerbase and he will be forced to accept our protection. 
\n \nIn the same time, we will increase hostile activity in Zaton through the bandits - we will pay some of them to make trouble in Zaton, thus increasing pressure on Beard to accept our protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_10">
		<text>Will killing Spartacus and Achilles not make us extremly unpopular with the Skadovsk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_11">
		<text>Yes - that is why you cannot kill them outright: you will have to arrange an accident or do it in disguise. We cannot be linked to these assassinations! Talk to Owl for the details, he should have an idea how to get them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_12">
		<text>Isn't the Zone harsh enough, do we now need to kill fellow Loners?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_13">
		<text>Are you a moron? Or some fucking pacifistic idealist? Do you think Sidorovich achieved his influence by asking nicely? Only because you are not able to see the violence does not mean it is not there! 
		The Zone is not a fucking birthday party, it's ride or die here - you have to be willing to fight for your place, because the next motherfucker will not think twice about putting a bullet in your brain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_14">
		<text>Relax, I understand - you're right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_15">
		<text>All I'm saying is that there might be another way. Let me at least try to convince Beard that working with us is better for him and the Skadovsk. Besides - it's also good for business, more men on our side.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_16">
		<text>Maybe you're not so stupid after all. Do you have another question or can we proceed with business?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_17">
		<text>You're a fucking moron. \n \n... \n \nFine, but don't fuck it up! It will be harder if they know that we're coming for them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_18">
		<text>Alright, where do we begin?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_19">
		<text>Go see Owl - he will tell you what to do. We'll stay in touch if there is anything coming up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_20">
		<text>Wait, I have a question.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_21">
		<text>What is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_22">
		<text>Alright, where do we begin?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_23">
		<text>How should I know? But if you change your mind and want to go with our plan - go see Owl.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_24">
		<text>Alright, I'll head to the Skadovsk now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="marlo_stanfield_11_25">
		<text>Alright, I'll head to the Skadovsk now.</text>
	</string>




<string id="achilles_joke_0_0">	
	<text>Several centuries ago, the Pope decreed that all the Jews had to convert to Catholicism or leave Italy. 
	There was a huge outcry from the Jewish community, so the Pope offered a deal. He'd have a religious debate with the leader of the Jewish community. 
	If the Jews won, they could stay in Italy; if the Pope won, they'd have to convert or leave.
	The Jewish people met and picked an aged and wise Rabbi to represent them in the debate.
	However, as the Rabbi spoke no Italian, and the Pope spoke no Hebrew, they agreed that it would be a 'silent' debate.
	On the chosen day, the Pope and the Rabbi sat opposite each other. \n
The Pope raised his hand and showed three fingers. \n
The Rabbi looked back and raised one finger. \n
Next, the Pope waved his finger around his head. The Rabbi pointed to the ground where he sat. \n
The Pope brought out a communion wafer and a chalice of wine. \n
The Rabbi pulled out an apple. \n
With that, the Pope stood up and declared himself beaten and said that the Rabbi was too clever. The Jews could stay in Italy!
Later the cardinals met with the Pope and asked him what had happened. The Pope said, 'First I held up three fingers to represent the Trinity. 
He responded by holding up a single finger to remind me there is still only one God common to both our beliefs.' 
'Then, I waved my finger around my head to show him that God was all around us. 
He responded by pointing to the ground to show that God was also right here with us.' 
'Finally, I pulled out the wine and wafer to show that God absolves us of all our sins. 
He pulled out an apple to remind me of the original sin.' 'He bested me at every move and I could not continue!' \n

Meanwhile, the Jewish community gathered to ask the Rabbi how he had won. 
'I don't have a clue!!!' the Rabbi said. 'First, he told me that we had three days to get out of Italy, so I gave him the finger.' 
Then he tells me that the whole country would be cleared of Jews, so I told him that we were staying right here.' 
And then what?' asked a woman. Who knows...' said the Rabbi. 'He took out his lunch, so I took out mine!'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="achilles_joke_0_1">
		<text>Hahahaha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="achilles_joke_0_2">
		<text>Not very funny.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="achilles_joke_0_3">
		<text>Ah it's great to drink with a man who understands humor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="achilles_joke_0_4">
		<text>That's because you have a potato instead of a heart my friend. Don't worry, one day I'll make you smile.</text>
	</string>

---- What a Night ----

<string id="sasha_tolstoy_1_0">
		<text>Hey man, how you're doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_1_1">
		<text>Horrible, my head is splitting itself.</text>
	</string>
	
	
<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_0">
		<text>Hey man, how you're doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_1">
		<text>I'm doing formidable my friend, do you want a shot?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_2">
		<text>You seem to be in high spirit, what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_3">
		<text>God smiled upon me my friend, my financial worries are no more!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_4">
		<text>Congrats!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_5">
		<text>Here have a drink with me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_6">
		<text>Sure let it flow!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_7">
		<text>Nah, I'm fine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_8">
		<text>Aaaah... \n \n C'mon, between the first and the second, the break is short!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_9">
		<text>You don't want, as you want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_10">
		<text>I can only agree with you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_11">
		<text>Thanks, but I don't want to become drunk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_12">
		<text>Here have some meat to chase the burn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_13">
		<text>Thanks. So tell me, what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_14">
		<text>You won't believe it! Yesterday I was drinking with the boys and we played some cards. My luck turned bad and I lost all my money to Andrey.
	So, this morning I set out in order to make my money back - I figured if I managed to hunt some Flesh or Boars, I could sell their parts for some good money. I set off a bit later int the morning, but
	the sun was heavy, so I decided to take a short rest in the shadow of the old Church: I had a few bites and some sips of Vodka - to fight my headache, you understand?
	Suddenly I heard some guys talking behind the wall,  what a foul language, you can't imagine! Fuck, I thought, tongues like this only grow on these Renegade Gopniks,
	so I took my feet into my hands and ran away to the north. Luckily they didn't see me, so my skin was safe... might have forgotten my bottle though now that I think of it.
	Fuck it! I bypassed the cemetery and made my way to the pond -
	I figured that maybe I might catch some of these pigs watering. Aah, my friend, my intuition was right, there were two pigs taking a rest on the shore. 
	I snuck up and BAM - shot and missed. My hands were probably still shaky from yesterday evening... doesn't matter! The two pigs squeal up taking off in the direction of the burned farmstead. 
	I lunch myself in pursuit, but I gave those two such a fright that one run straight into the flame anomaly! The pillar engulfed him immediatly, roasting him on the spot.
	I cursed the heavens, impossible to make money of that pile of ashes now I thought. But then I noticed it... the pig probably kicked a Flame while running through the anomaly,
	and the artifact landed outside, ripe for the taking! Can you imagine it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_15">
		<text>Incredible! What luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_16">
		<text>Indeed, indeed! Let's have a drink to that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_17">
		<text>Let's drink!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_18">
		<text>Ah my friend, I quite enjoy drinking with you! Let's have another one, to friendship!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_19">
		<text>I like drinking with you too! To friendship!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_20">
		<text>Here my friend, have a bite.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_21">
		<text>Alright, my turn to propose a toast!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_22">
		<text>Let it hear!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_23">
		<text>Our will shall not break, we drank, drink and will drink again!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_24">
		<text>To you, to us, to our Zone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_25">
		<text>God is not stupid, he loves fives!</text>
	</string>


<string id="barman_sektor_gaza_0_0">
		<text>Here is your CD.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_sektor_gaza_0_1">
		<text>My man!</text>
	</string>



---- Rush to the North and Brainscorcher reactions ------

<string id="fanatic_north_1_0">
		<text>About the rookie supplies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_1_1">
		<text>Yeah?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_1_2">
		<text>I gathered the supplies. Here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_1_8">
		<text>I need more time to gather the supplies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_1_9">
		<text>Fucking awesome dude! You are a hero to me and I'll make sure that everyone hears about your generosity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_1_10">
		<text>Awesome dude! You are a rare breed in the Zone, I'll make sure that everyone hears about your generosity.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="fanatic_north_1_11">
		<text>Great! You are a great benefactor for the rookies, I'll make sure that everyone hears about your generosity.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="fanatic_north_1_12">
		<text>Excellent! You are a benefactor for the rookies, I'll make sure that everyone hears about your generosity.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="fanatic_north_1_13">
		<text>Perfect! Thanks a lot for your help, I'll make sure that everyone hears about your help.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="fanatic_north_1_14">
		<text>Cool, thanks a lot! I'll make sure the other hear about your help.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="fanatic_north_1_15">
		<text>No rush! Take your time.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="fanatic_north_0_0">
		<text>Hy Fanat, how are you doing? What happened since I left?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_1">
		<text>The usual my man, the usual. You on the other hand - I heard rumors about your deads! People say it was you who shut down the Brainscorcher? Is it true?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_2">
		<text>Yeah I did! Was an horrible experience though - I don't plan on repeating it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_3">
		<text>I'm glad you're making a name for yourself out here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_4">
		<text>Yeah I get by - also thanks to your training! You really helped me out back in the days.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_5">
		<text>Yeah thanks! It's not easy - a lot of hardship and no one helps you out. But hard work pays off, and now I'm a selfmade man!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_6">
		<text>Good that you mention the training, I've got a favor to ask of you. 
			You see, I try to help the rookies around here out and provide them with some of the basic tools to survive in this environment - you know, like I helped you... 
			The problem is, these tools are expensive - I try to pay for it out of my own pocket, but Sidorovich doesn't pay that well to guard this village and he says it's against his philosophy to give hand-outs... so I have to resort to donations. 
			Some of my former pupils kick back some money if they are able to - the problem is, they are few in number as they either die or got generosity sucked out of them by the Zone. \n \n Do you think you could make a small donations in order to help the future generation to get on their feet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_7">
		<text>Eeeh... yeah sure. Say, I've got a favor to ask of you. You see, I try to help the rookies around here out and provide them with some of the basic tools to survive in this environment - you know, like I helped you... 
			The problem is, these tools are expensive - I try to pay for it out of my own pocket, but Sidorovich doesn't pay that well to guard this village and he says it's against his philosophy to give hand-outs... so I have to resort to donations. 
			Some of my former pupils kick back some money if they are able to - the problem is, they are few in number as they either die or got generosity sucked out of them by the Zone. \n \n Do you think you could make a small donations in order to help the future generation to get on their feet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_8">
		<text>Sure man, I'm always glad to give back when I'm able! What do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_9">
		<text>Depends, what do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_10">
		<text>Eeeh... I don't know man, you know in the current economic... I barely scrape by myself!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_11">
		<text>I don't believe in hand outs!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_12">
		<text>I'm glad to hear that! Enough material to kit out three rookies would be great! Say, three Echo detectors, three bottles of Nemiroff and thirty shells of buckshot.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_13">
		<text>I would need enough material to kit out a couple of rookies, ideally for three rookies... Say, three Echo detectors, three bottles of Nemiroff and thirty shells of buckshot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_14">
		<text>I understand, forget I asked about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_15">
		<text>I see... Forget I asked...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_16">
		<text>I can do that, no problem! I'll be back with goods!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_17">
		<text>Shiieet man, only for three rookies? Are you sure you don't need more?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_18">
		<text>Damn, I have to say, that's quite steep...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_181">
		<text>That's too much, I'm sorry, I can't help you out.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_19">
		<text>Great, thank you Stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_20">
		<text>To be honest, I need much more, but I don't want to abuse your generosity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_21">
		<text>Understandable. Two of each would also help out a lot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_22">
		<text>I appreciate what you're doing here for the rookies and I want to help you out. I'll come back with ten of each.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_23">
		<text>I appreciate what you're doing here for the rookies and I want to help you out. I'll come back with five of each.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_24">
		<text>I appreciate what you're doing here for the rookies and I want to help you out. I'll come back with four of each.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_25">
		<text>On second thoughts, three of each is already a lot, but I will do it for you. I'll come back with the material.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_26">
		<text>Ten? That would be fucking awesome, thanks a lot!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_27">
		<text>Five? Wow, that would help the rookies out a lot! Thanks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_28">
		<text>That's very generous. Thanks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_29">
		<text>I understand, three is all I ask for! Thank you a lot for your help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_30">
		<text>Yeah I can do two. I'll come back with the material.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_31">
		<text>One of each will have to suffice, I'll give you back what you once gave me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_32">
		<text>Alright, thank you for helping the rookies out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_33">
		<text>I guess that's better than nothing. Thank you nevertheless.</text>
	</string>




<string id="barkeep_north_0_0">
		<text>You seem to have a full-house here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_0_1">
		<text>And all thanks to you! By disabling the Brainscorcher you opened up the north for anyone who dares to go! 
			You triggered a rush for the north - and people gather here to buy supplies before setting off! Here, a drink on the house - you deserved it! \n \n
			If you're looking to make some money, now is a great opportunity! Prices are soaring, I hope you don't need any supplies as demand is huge at the moment.</text>
	</string>





















	
</string_table>
